Guide to the Charles Edwards Papers 1936-1985 (Bulk 1956-1967) MC.97
New York University Archives
Charles Edwards Papers
1936-1985
1956-1967
New York University Archives
Edwards, Charles Mundy, Jr.
MC.97
2 Linear Feet 2 linear feet (3 boxes)
This collection contains the professional papers of Charles Edwards, Dean of the School of Retailing from 1946 to 1971. Materials include course materials, personal letters, clippings, analyses of local retail establishments, and advertisements.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject heading then chronologically thereafter.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
Subject Files
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the professional papers of Charles Edwards, Dean of the School of Retailing from 1946 to 1971. Materials include course materials, personal letters, clippings, analyses of local retail establishments, and advertisements.
Historical/Biographical Note
Charles Mundy Edwards, Jr. was born in 1905 in Richmond, VA. After receiving a B.S. in Business Administration from the University of Richmond, Edwards came to NYU to earn his Masters at the School of Retailing and then his Doctorate at the Graduate School of Business Administration. Retailing had been taught at NYU since 1916, when NYU first offered courses through the School of Pedagogy for training in retail. This Training School for Teachers of Retail Selling became the School of Retailing on April 25, 1921. In 1964, NYU converted the school into the Institute of Retail Management, and made it a unit of the Schools of Business. Edwards returned to NYU in 1930 as a lecturer at the School of Retailing. He later became a professor and in 1946 became Dean of the School. In September 1971 he resigned his position and was succeeded by Elmar O. Schaller. Edwards died in October 1985 in Summit, N.J.
Sources:
Edwards, Charles, Biographical File, New York University Archives
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection. Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted. Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the University Archives by Mrs. Charles M. Edwards, Jr. in 1987.
Professional education.; Retailing.; Edwards, Charles Mundy, Jr.; New York University. Institute of Retail Management
- Series I: Subject Files
  - 25th Anniversary of the School of Retailing, 1956-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Artist's Professional League, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Army Exchange Service - Administrative, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Army Exchange Service - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Army Exchange Service - Course Materials, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Army Exchange Service - "Chaning PX Minds and Methods in Paris", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Consumer Cooperatives, 1945-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Course Materials - Regulation of Retail Advertising, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Course Materials - Regulation of Labeling and Grading, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Course Materials, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Course Materials, 1948-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Course Materials - Session 8 - The Changing Consumer, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Course Materials - Restraints upon Retail Competition, External vs. Internal Regulation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Course Materials - Organization Charts (A - L), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Course Materials - Organization Charts (M), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Course Materials - Organization Charts (N - Z), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Course Materials - Retailers Manual of Taxes and Regulations, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Course Materials - Session 13 - The Impact of Automation on Retailing, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Course Materials - Session 14 - The Measurement of Productivity in Retailing, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Course Materials - Session 15 - Tradition vs Transition in Retailing, Emerging Trends, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Course Materials - Seminar, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Course Materials, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Course Materials - Sources of Supply of Consumer Goods, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Definition of Terms, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Faculty NYU- School of Retailing, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Filenes's Ad Study, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Franchise Company Data, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Franchising, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Gibson Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gibson Course Materials, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Gibson, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gibson, 1964, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gibson, 1964 -Nassau Convention, Bahamas, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gibson, 1964 -New Orleans Convention, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gibson, 1965 - Course Materials, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gibson, 1965 - San Juan Convention, Puerto Rico, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gibson, 1966 - Hong Kong Convention, China, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Gibson, 1967, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Gibson, 1967 - Acapulco Convention, Mexico, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Gibson, 1967- Speech, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Gibson Publicity, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gibson Resumes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Journal of Retailing & Advertising and Selling, 1945-1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letters of Congratulations, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Letters of Congratulations, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Letters of Thanks, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - NYU Communication with Gibson, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - NYU- School of Retailing - Promotion and Salary, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Obituaries, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Observe Ad Contest & Publicity (Gimbel Brothers), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Observe Ad Contest & Publicity (Gimbel Brothers), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Open House- School of Retailing, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Protection of Health and Public Welfare, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Publicity, 1937-1955 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Publicity, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Publicity, 1960-1984 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Retail Advertising and Sales Promotion( Reviews of 1st Edition and printing of book), 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Retail Outlets, 1936-1966 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Retail Trade, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Shillito's - Part I, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Shillito's - Part II, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Speech, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Shillito's - The John Shillito Company, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Student Paper, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Supermarkets- SMI, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Workshop in Retail Advertising, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 66)